A Guide to the R. Bruce Merrifield papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA415
Rockefeller Archive Center
R. Bruce Merrifield papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1935-2009
Rockefeller Archive Center
Merrifield, Bruce (Robert Bruce)
Rockefeller University
FA415
157.17 Cubic Feet 411 document boxes
File Plan
Former Classification: I 450 M552
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Bruce Merrifield, known as Bruce, was born on July 15, 1921 in Fort Worth, Texas. His family moved to California in 1923, and Merrifield graduated from Montebello High School in 1939. He attended Pasadena Junior College and the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), graduating with a degree in chemistry in 1943. In 1944, he returned to UCLA for graduate school, conducting his thesis research under the supervision of Max S. Dunn. He received his PhD in 1949, married Elizabeth "Libby" Furlong the day after his graduation, and moved to New York City to take up a fellowship in the laboratory of D. Wayne Woolley at the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research the day after his wedding.
Merrifield's work in Woolley's lab included synthesizing peptides, a process that could take months or even years. In 1959, Merrifield proposed an idea for what would eventually become the process of solid phase peptide synthesis to Woolley, who gave him permission to experiment. In 1962, Merrifield published an article establishing solid phase peptide synthesis (SPPS) as a less time-consuming alternative to old peptide synthesis methods. During his tenure at Rockefeller, Merrifield devoted much of his time and research to continued exploration of solid phase peptide synthesis, and many students and colleagues joined him to expand his investigations.
Merrifield was awarded the Lasker Basic Medical Research Award in 1969, was elected as a member of the National Academy of Sciences in 1972, and received the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1984 for "his development of methodology for chemical synthesis on a solid matrix."
R. Bruce Merrifield passed away on May 14, 2006.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the collection documents R. Bruce Merrifield's tenure at the Rockefeller University, and includes biographical materials, correspondence, laboratory notes and notebooks, and manuscripts and reprints. The collection includes files related to some of Merrifield's students and colleagues, and includes a small portion of D. Wayne Woolley materials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into seven distinct series based on subject matter and media:
Series 1, Biographical Materials
Series 2, Correspondence
Series 3, Subject Files
Series 4, Laboratory Files
Series 5, Manuscripts and Publications
Series 6, Talks, Trips, and Commitments
Series 7, Audio-Visual and Oversized
Peptides; Proteins -- Synthesis; Chemistry
- Biographical Materials, 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Autobiography (Box 1, Folder 1-4, Box 2, Folder 5-7)
  - Autobiography, Last Typed Original (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Autobiography, Outline (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Autobiography, Revisions (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Autobiography, Seeman's Computer Printout that I Corrected and Sent Back, 1988 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Autobiography, Various Edited Versions by Seeman and Westheimer (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    Scope and Contents
    Folder 14 includes: "Automated Solid Phase Synthesis of Thymosin" by Wang, Makofske, Bach, and Merrifield "The Mechanism of Thiolytic Removal of the Dithiasuccinoyl Amino Protecting Group" by Barany "Multi-Detachable Resin Supports for Solid Phase Fragment Synthesis" by Tam, Tjoeng, and Merrifield
  - Bibliography, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bibliography and C.V., 2003 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Biographical Information and Articles (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Biographies and Clippings (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Biographical Notes (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Biographies and Clippings (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Biography (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Biography (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Calendars, 1984-1986; 1989 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Calendars, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Calendars, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Consultantships (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - First Version Edited by Seeman, Autobiography (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Lasker (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - "News and Notes" (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - "News and Notes", 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Nobel Prize, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 33-34)
  - Nobel Prize Lecture, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Old Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Personal (Box 6, Folder 37)
    Includes: Press Conference Materials, "The Rockefeller University and Merck Sharp & Dohme Research Laboratories" Biography of Robert Bruce Merrifield Biography of Bernd Gutte Press Release, "First Total Synthesis of an Enzyme Announced Simultaneously by Rockefeller University and Merck Sharp & Dohme Laboratories Scientists" Press Release, "Background on Synthesis of Ribonuclease" Biography Brief on Dr. Ralph F. Hirschmann
  - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Photographs, Colleagues (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Photographs, Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Photographs, Nobel Prize, 1984 (Box 6, Box 41)
  - Photographs, Portraits (Box 6, Box 42)
  - Profiles (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - "Research Profile," Spring 1985 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Rockefeller University Genealogy/Family Tree (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Seeman - Chapter for August, Autobiography (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - "Summary of Achievements of R.B. Merrifield", 1994 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Autobiography (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Correspondence, 2
  - A (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - A-Ac (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Active Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Ad-Ak (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Al (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Am (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - American (Box 8, Folder 55-56)
  - An (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Andreu (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Ap-Az (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Arshady (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - A to Z Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - B (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - B-Bal (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Bar (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Bas-Bay (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Baserga, Renato (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Be (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Bead Sorter COPAS (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Beckman (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Benedetti (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Bhargava (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Bi-Bl (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - "Biochemistry" (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - "Biochemistry" (Box 10, Folder 73A)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Folder restricted - contains closed materials.
  - Biron (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - Bo (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Boman (Box 11, Folder 76-77)
  - Boman and KabiGen (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Br-By (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Bronk (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Bronk (Box 11, Folder 80A)
  - Burley (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - C (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Ca-Cat (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Cal Tech (Box 12, Folder 84)
  - Caporale (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - Cathay Award, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 86)
  - Ce-Cl (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - Centennial, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - Chandra (Box 12, Folder 89)
  - Chillemi (Box 12, Folder 90)
  - "Chinese Chemical Letters" (Box 12, Folder 91)
  - Choppin (Box 12, Folder 92)
  - CIBA (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - City of New York Parks and Recreation (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - Co-Cz (Box 13, Folder 95-96)
  - Colgate University (Box 13, Folder 97)
  - COPE Award (Box 13, Folder 98)
  - Cowburn (Box 13, Folder 99)
  - Cowburn, NIMR (Box 13, Folder 100)
  - CPS 2000 (6th Chinese Peptide Symposium) (Box 13, Folder 101)
  - CREMONA Fund (Box 13, Folder 102)
  - Crowley Book (Box 13, Folder 103)
  - D (Box 13, Folder 104, Box 14, Folder 105-106)
  - de Duve (Box 14, Folder 107)
  - De Grado (Box 14, Folder 108)
  - de Lencastre (Box 14, Folder 109)
  - Di Marchi (Box 14, Folder 110)
  - Djerassi (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - DNA Technology Center (Box 14, Folder 112)
  - Dow Chemical Company (Box 14, Folder 113)
  - Drell (Box 14, Folder 114)
  - Dunn (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - E (Box 14, Folder 116-117)
  - E.I. du Pont de Meours and Co. (Box 15, Folder 118)
  - Eaker (Box 15, Folder 119)
  - Eiger (Box 15, Folder 120)
  - Enamelon (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - Erds (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - Erickson (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - F (Box 15, Folder 124-127)
  - FASEB (Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology) (Box 16, Folder 128)
  - Felix (Box 16, Folder 129)
  - Ferrofluidics (Box 16, Folder 130)
  - Flanagan (Box 16, Folder 131)
  - Floyd (Box 16, Folder 132)
  - Fruton (Box 16, Folder 133)
  - G (Box 16, Folder 134-135, Box 17, Folder 136-137)
  - Gairdner Foundation (Box 17, Folder 138)
  - Gordon Research Conference (Box 17, Folder 139)
  - Guillemin (Box 17, Folder 140)
  - Gutte (Box 17, Folder 141)
  - H (Box 17, Folder 142, Box 18, Folder 143-146)
  - Hansen (Box 19, Folder 147)
  - Hill, David (Box 19, Folder 148)
  - Hirschmann, Ralph F., Correspondence, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 149)
  - Hodges (Box 19, Folder 150)
  - Hou, Jian-Min (Box 19, Folder 151)
  - Houghten, Richard A. (Box 19, Folder 152)
  - Hruby (Box 19, Folder 153)
  - Hudson (Box 19, Folder 154)
  - Huguenin (Box 19, Folder 155)
  - I (Box 19, Folder 156-157, Box 20, Folder 158)
  - International Journal of Peptide and Protein Research (Box 20, Folder 159)
  - Izumi (Box 20, Folder 160)
  - J (Box 20, Folder 161-162)
  - Job Candidates, 1970-1979 (Box 21, Folder 163)
  - Job Candidates, 1980-1987 (Box 21, Folder 164)
  - Job Requests (Box 21, Folder 165)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society (Box 21, Folder 166)
  - Journal of Medical Chemistry (Box 21, Folder 167)
  - Journal of Organic Chemistry (Box 21, Folder 168)
  - Journal of Peptide Research (Box 21, Folder 169)
  - Journal of Solid-Phase Biochemistry (Box 22, Folder 170)
  - K (Box 22, Folder 171-173)
  - Kaiser (Box 22, Folder 174)
  - Kamen (Box 22, Folder 175)
  - Kapoor (Box 22, Folder 176)
  - Kelly (Box 22, Folder 177)
  - Kenner Bakerian Lecture (Box 23, Folder 178)
  - Knight (Box 23, Folder 179)
  - Knobler (Box 23, Folder 180)
  - Kobayashi (Box 23, Folder 181)
  - Kreeger (Box 23, Folder 182)
  - Kubiak (Box 23, Folder 183)
  - Kunkel (Box 23, Folder 184)
  - Kuriyan (Box 23, Folder 185)
  - L (Box 23, Folder 186-189)
  - Lasker Awards (Box 24, Folder 190)
  - Lederberg (Box 24, Folder 191)
  - Lederberg to Merrifield (Box 24, Folder 192)
  - Lehrer (Box 24, Folder 193)
  - Lerner (Box 24, Folder 194)
  - Levine (Box 24, Folder 195)
  - Libby's List of Colleagues, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 196)
  - Live (Box 24, Folder 197)
  - M (Box 24, Folder 198-199, Box 25, Folder 200-202)
  - Magainin (Box 25, Folder 203)
  - Mailing List, 9th European Peptide Symposium (Box 25, Folder 204)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 25, Folder 205)
  - Manatt (Box 25, Folder 206)
  - Mantell (Box 25, Folder 207)
  - Marinsky (Gordon Conference) (Box 25, Folder 208)
  - Martin (Box 26, Folder 209)
  - Mcs, Imre (Box 26, Folder 210)
  - Meinhofer (Box 26, Folder 211)
  - Miscellaneous Mail, 1952-1970s (Box 26, Folder 212)
  - Mitchell (Box 26, Folder 213)
  - Mojsov, Svetlana, Correspondence, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 214)
  - Moore (Box 26, Folder 215)
  - Muir (Box 27, Folder 216)
  - N (Box 27, Folder 217-221)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box 28, Folder 222-224)
  - National Patent Development Corporation (Box 28, Folder 225)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 28, Folder 226)
  - Nobel Prize, 2001-2002 (Box 28, Folder 227)
  - Novo-Norodisk (Box 28, Folder 228)
  - Nurse (Box 28, Folder 229)
  - O (Box 29, Folder 230)
  - Office of the President (Box 29, Folder 231)
  - Ovchinnikov (Box 29, Folder 232)
  - P (Box 29, Folder 233-235, Box 30, Folder 236)
  - Patchornik (Box 30, Folder 237)
  - Paull (Immuno-Augmentative Therapy) (Box 30, Folder 238)
  - "Peptide Research" (Box 30, Folder 239)
  - Pieczenik (Box 30, Folder 240)
  - PNAS (Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences) (Box 30, Folder 241)
  - Porath (Box 30, Folder 242)
  - Q (Box 30, Folder 243)
    Includes: Woolley correspondence
  - R (Box 31, Folder 244-247, Box 32, Folder 248)
  - Ragnarsson (Box 32, Folder 249)
  - Reactive Polymers (Box 32, Folder 250)
  - Reeke and Search Committe (Box 32, Folder 250-251)
  - Robinson (Box 33, Folder 253-254)
  - Rockefeller University (Box 33, Folder 255)
  - S (Box 33, Folder 256, Box 34, Folder 257-261, Box 35, Folder 262-263)
  - Sakmar (Box 35, Folder 264)
  - Satterthwait (Box 35, Folder 265)
  - Schwarz Synthesizer (Box 35, Folder 266)
  - Seitz (Box 35, Folder 267)
  - Shai (Box 35, Folder 268)
  - Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research (Box 35, Folder 269)
  - Stark (Box 36, Folder 270)
  - Stein-Moore (Box 36, Folder 271)
  - T (Box 36, Folder 272-274)
  - Tam (Box 36, Folder 275, Box 37, Folder 276-281, Box 38, Folder 282)
  - To File (Box 38, Folder 283-284)
  - Tuition (Box 38, Folder 285)
  - U (Box 38, Folder 286)
  - UCLA (University of California, Los Angeles) (Box 39, Folder 287)
  - Unfoldered Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 288-289)
  - Unfoldered Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 289A)
  - Unfoldered Correspondence, 2000-2004 (Box 39, Folder 290, Box 40, Folder 291-294, Box 41, Folder 295-296)
  - Unlabeled Folder (Box 41, Folder 297-298)
  - Unlabeled Folder, 1984-1985 (Box 42, Folder 299)
  - V (Box 42, Folder 300-301)
  - Varshavsky (Box 42, Folder 302)
  - Vega (Box 42, Folder 303)
  - W (Box 42, Folder 304, Box 43, Folder 305-306)
  - Wang, Chang Yi, United Biomedical (Box 43, Folder 307)
  - Warshawsky, Abraham (Box 43, Folder 308)
  - "Who's Who" (Box 43, Folder 309)
  - Wiesel (Box 44, Folder 310)
  - Wolf Prize (Box 44, Folder 311)
  - Woolley (Box 44, Folder 312)
  - X (Box 44, Folder 313)
  - Y (Box 44, Folder 314)
  - Z (Box 44, Folder 315)
  - Zabriskie (Callisto Pharmaceuticals) (Box 44, Folder 316)
  - Zahn (Box 44, Folder 317)
- Subject Files, 3
  - II A, Non-Swelling Polymers, References (Box 44, Folder 318)
  - II A, PEG, References (Box 44, Folder 319)
  - II B, Protecting Groups, Variables for Removal of N and Side Chains, References (Box 44, Folder 320)
  - II B, Specific Protecting Groups for N and Side Chains, References (Box 45, Folder 321)
  - II C, Removal from Linkers, References (Box 45, Folder 322)
  - II C, Catalyzed H2 Pd0, References (Box 45, Folder 323)
  - II D, Activation and Coupling Reagents, Activation Methods, References (Box 45, Folder 324)
  - II D, Cause and Correction, Text and Notes, References (Box 45, Folder 325)
  - II D, Coupling, Monitor Coupling Rates, References (Box 45, Folder 326)
  - II D, Coupling to Salt, References (Box 45, Folder 327)
  - II D, References (Box 45, Folder 328)
  - II E, Deprotection: Cleavage, References (Box 46, Folder 329)
  - II F, Racemization, References (Box 46, Folder 330)
  - II F, Side Reactions, References (Box 46, Folder 331)
  - II G, Purification, References (Box 46, Folder 332)
  - III, Apparatus, References (Box 46, Folder 333)
  - III D, Large Scale Synthesis, References (Box 46, Folder 334)
  - III F, Purification, Characterization, Identification, References (Box 46, Folder 335)
  - IV A-F, Multiple Synthesis on...Columns Membranes, References (Box 46, Folder 336)
  - V A, Cyclic Peptides, References (Box 46, Folder 337)
  - V B, S-S Bonds, References (Box 46, Folder 338)
  - V C, Amino Acid Derivatives, References (Box 46, Folder 339)
  - V D, Pseudopeptide, References (Box 46, Folder 340)
  - V F, Glycopeptides, References (Box 47, Folder 341)
  - V H, Synthetic Vaccines, References (Box 47, Folder 342)
  - V J, Oligosaccharides, References (Box 47, Folder 343)
  - V K, Nucleotides, References (Box 47, Folder 344)
  - V L, PNA (Peptide Nucleic Acids), References (Box 47, Folder 345)
  - V M, Other Uses of SPS, References (Box 47, Folder 346)
  - 80th Birthday Symposium, 2001 (Box 47, Folder 347)
  - ACS (American Chemical Society) Award, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 348)
  - Active Files, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 349)
  - Ad (Adenylate) Cyclase and Binding Assays (Box 48, Folder 350)
  - Aldehydes and Double Bonds (Box 48, Folder 351)
  - Allfrey, Proteins into Nucleus (Box 48, Folder 352)
  - Alpha 1 Biomedicals (Box 48, Folder 353)
  - Alpha 1 Biomedicals, Inc. (Box 48, Folder 354)
  - Alteon (Box 48, Folder 355-358)
  - Alteon Scientific Advistory Meeting, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 359)
  - American Chemical Society, National Historic Chemical Landmark (Box 49, Folder 360)
  - Amphipathic Helix, Conformation (Box 49, Folder 361)
  - Antibacterial Peptides (Box 49, Folder 362)
  - Antibodies (Box 49, Folder 363)
  - Applied Biosystems, Inc. (Box 49, Folder 364, Box 50, Folder 365-367)
  - Assay Protocol, 1984-2007 (Box 50, Folder 368)
  - Atrix (Box 51, Folder 369-372, Box 52, Folder 373-375, Box 53, Folder 376-379, Box 54, Folder 380-384, Box 55, Folder 385-387, Box 56, Folder 388-391, Box 57, Folder 392-395, Box 58, Folder 396-399, Box 59, Folder 400-402, Box 60, Folder 403-404)
  - Atrix/Vipont (Box 60, Folder 405)
  - Availability of Space for Reactive Sites in Resins (Box 60, Folder 406)
  - Beckman (Box 60, Folder 407, Box 61, Folder 408)
  - Beckman Scintillation Counter (Box 61, Folder 409)
  - Bioassay Analysis (Box 61, Folder 410)
  - Biosensors (Unson) (Box 61, Folder 411)
  - Bivalent Ligands (Box 61, Folder 412)
  - Blocking Unreacted Chains, 1962-1968 (Box 61, Folder 413)
  - Bulletins on Special Reagents (Box 61, Folder 414)
  - Burke (Wyatt, Gerber, Burke, and Badie - Patents) (Box 61, Folder 415)
  - Butyloxycarbonyl Amino Acid Data (Box 61, Folder 416)
  - Catalytic Antibodies (Box 61, Folder 417)
  - Catalytic Antibody Plans and Reprints (Box 61, Folder 418)
  - Catalytic Antibody Reprints (Box 62, Folder 419)
  - CD Analysis (Box 62, Folder 420)
  - CD Data on Glucagon (Box 62, Folder 421)
  - CD ORD Tam (Circular Dichroism) (Box 62, Folder 422)
  - Cecropin (Box 62, Folder 423)
  - Cecropin A(1-33) Figures and Data (Box 63, Folder 424)
  - Cecropin, All Recent Cecropin Data (Box 63, Folder 425)
  - Cecropin Data to be Sorted (Box 63, Folder 426)
  - Cecropin, Inventories and Summaries (Box 63, Folder 427)
  - Cecropin-Melittin (Box 63, Folder 428, Box 64, Folder 429-431)
  - Cecropin, Miscellaneous Cecropin Data (Box 64, Folder 432)
  - Cecropin, Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 64, Folder 433)
  - Cecropin, New Cecropin Experiments to be Done, 1997 (Box 64, Folder 434)
  - Cecropin Papers (Box 64, Folder 435)
  - Cecropin, Plans for Experiments (Box 64, Folder 436)
  - Cecropin, Recent Cecropin Plans, Data, etc., 1992-1996 (Box 65, Folder 437)
  - Center for Advanced Biotechnology and Medicine (Box 65, Folder 438-439)
  - Centocor (Box 65, Folder 440)
  - Chemistry (Faculty) (Box 65, Folder 441)
  - Chemistry Search Committee (Box 66, Folder 442)
  - China (Box 66, Folder 443)
  - Chloromethylation (Box 66, Folder 444)
  - Chou-Fasman Conformation, etc. (Box 66, Folder 445)
  - C-M-14 Paper, Affinity Chromatography, 1973 (Box 66, Folder 446)
  - Combinatorial High-Throughput (Box 66, Folder 447)
  - Computer Graphics (Directions) (Box 66, Folder 448)
  - Conductance, Experiment in Dr. Olaf S. Aandersen's Lab, Traces (Box 66, Folder 449)
  - Conformation, Swelling, Aggregation (Box 66, Folder 450)
  - Cross, George A.M. (Box 67, Folder 451)
  - C-Terminal Hemoglobin (Box 67, Folder 452)
  - Cytochrome C (Box 67, Folder 453)
  - Deprotection of Glu(OB21), 1972-1973 (Box 67, Folder 454)
  - Depsipeptides (Box 67, Folder 455-456)
  - Desacetylthymosin 1 (Box 67, Folder 457)
  - Diagonal Methods, 1961-1967 (Box 67, Folder 458)
  - Diffusion (Comparison of Diffusion and Coupling Reaction Rates) (Box 67, Folder 459)
  - Dinucleotides (Box 68, Folder 460-461)
  - Disaster Plan (Box 68, Folder 462)
  - Disulfide-RNase Problem, 1971-1972 (Box 68, Folder 463)
  - D-Peptides, Channels (Box 68, Folder 464)
  - Enamelon (Box 69, Folder 465-469, Box 70, Folder 470-471)
  - Enzyme (Box 70, Folder 472)
  - Enzymes (Box 70, Folder 473)
  - Equilibrium Dialysis, 1970-1974 (Box 70, Folder 474)
  - Experiment to Avoid Aggregation, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 475)
  - Experimental Procedures (Box 71, Folder 476)
  - Faculty Administration (Box 71, Folder 477)
  - Felix, Cecropin B, Roche (Box 71, Folder 478)
  - Ferredoxin (Box 71, Folder 479)
  - Film, "The Chemical Synthesis of Proteins" (Box 71, Folder 480)
    - Film, "The Chemical Synthesis of Proteins", 2016:FA415:001 (Box 71, Folder 480)
  - Film, "Enzyme Footage" (Box 71, Folder 481)
    - Film, "Enzyme Footage", 2016:FA415:002 (Box 71, Folder 481)
  - Fluorescence Experiment (Box 71, Folder 482)
  - Formal Trp Refs (Formyl/Tryptophan References) (Box 71, Folder 483)
  - Fourth Enzyme Mechanisms Conference, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1975 January 3-5 (Box 71, Folder 484)
  - Genetic Design, Inc. (Box 71, Folder 485)
  - Genome Project (Box 71, Folder 486, Box 72, Folder 487)
  - Glucagon (Box 72, Folder 488-489)
  - Glucagon Antagonists (Box 72, Folder 490)
  - Glucagon - Bill (Box 72, Folder 491)
  - Glucagon CD Analysis (Box 73, Folder 492)
  - Glucagon - Hruby - Current Status and Plans for Future, 1985 September 11 (Box 73, Folder 493)
  - Glucagon Receptors (Box 73, Folder 494)
  - Glucagon References, Design of Hormone Analogs VI (Box 73, Folder 495)
  - Glucagon References, Glucagon Chemical Synthesis VIII (Box 73, Folder 496)
  - Glucagon References, Library Searches (Box 73, Folder 497)
  - Glucagon References, Our Glucagon Papers IX (Box 73, Folder 498)
  - Glucagon References, Precursors IV (Box 73, Folder 499)
  - Glucagon References, Receptors III (Box 74, Folder 500)
  - Glucagon References, Receptors III2 (Box 74, Folder 501)
  - Glucagon References, Synth Analogs I (Box 74, Folder 502)
  - Glutathione Peptide, Bhargava et al. (Box 74, Folder 503)
  - Glycopeptide References (Box 74, Folder 504)
  - Grant Application, Bruce W. Erickson, 1980 (Box 75, Folder 505)
  - Hagenmaier Peptide (Box 75, Folder 506)
  - Hansen, Glucagon-Secretin Analogs (Box 75, Folder 507)
  - Helical Net (Diagrams) (Box 75, Folder 508)
  - Hetnarski, Antifungals (Box 75, Folder 509)
  - HF (Box 75, Folder 510)
  - HF, Tam (Box 75, Folder 511)
  - Hirschmann Award Nominations (Box 75, Folder 512, Box 76, Folder 513)
  - His(DNP) Experiments (Box 76, Folder 514)
  - Histone IV (Box 76, Folder 515)
  - HIV-1 Protease References (Box 76, Folder 516)
  - HIV-1 Protease Synthesis (Box 76, Folder 517)
  - HIV-1 Supplemental References (Box 76, Folder 518)
  - HMG Proteins (Box 76, Folder 519)
  - Hoffman-La Roche (Box 76, Folder 520)
  - HPLC Copies, Leu-eukephalin (Box 76, Folder 521)
  - Human Genome Project (Box 77, Folder 522)
  - Immunoglobulin (Box 77, Folder 523)
  - Immunoglobulin Synthesis (Box 77, Folder 524)
  - Immunology Reprints (Box 77, Folder 525)
  - Innate Antibodies (Box 77, Folder 526-527)
  - Innovair (Box 77, Folder 528)
  - Interferon Literature (Box 78, Folder 529)
  - Interferon Project with Sloan-Kettering, Original Plan and Samples (Box 78, Folder 530)
  - Interferon References (Box 78, Folder 531)
  - Interferon Sequences, Weissman, Taniguchi, 1980 (Box 78, Folder 532)
  - Interferon Workshop (Box 78, Folder 533)
  - I.R. Data, Cecropin (Box 78, Folder 534)
  - Japan Prize (Box 78, Folder 535)
  - Japan Trip, Spring 1971 (Box 78, Folder 536)
  - Kaiser-Kubiak (Box 78, Folder 537)
  - Kaiser, (Trimethylbomosilane) (Box 78, Folder 538)
  - Kinetics (Box 79, Folder 539-543)
  - Kinetics, Diffusion (Box 80, Folder 544)